地球形式的求救信号，SOS
Earth-style distress signal. SOS.
我用所有频段回复了一遍，长官，对方无应答
I've answered it on all frequencies, sir. They don't reply.
并非来自星舰，而是来自地面
Not a vessel, a ground source.
仪器显示信号来自该太阳系第三颗行星
The third planet in this solar system, according to my instruments.
就在正前方，确定是地球形式的信号
Directly ahead. Definitely an Earth-style signal.
我们离地球可有数百光年，史波克
We're hundreds of light-years from Earth, Mr. Spock.
此处甚远，既无殖民地也无星舰
No colonies or vessels out this far.
行星测量中，舰长，形状为扁圆体
Measuring the planet now, captain. Spheroid-shaped.
周长24874英里
Circumference, 24,874 miles.
质量，6乘10的21次方吨
Mass, 6 times 10-to-the-21 st-power tons.
平均密度，5.517
Mean density, 5.517.
大气成分…
Atmosphere...
氧气，氮气
...oxygen-nitrogen.
地球
Earth.
不是那个地球，而是另一个
Not the Earth. Another Earth.
另一个“地球”
Another Earth.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：kmdangdangli 土豆爱 Claire叶子
校对：心痕依 Micezhang xjCGI
第一季第八集 米莉
舰长日志，星历2713.5
Captain's log, stardate 2713.5:
距离我们的星系很遥远的地方
In the distant reaches of our galaxy,
我们有个惊人的发现
we have made an astonishing discovery:
一颗行星发出地球形式的无线电信号
Earth-type radio signals coming from a planet
这颗行星简直就是地球的翻版
which apparently is an exact duplicate of the Earth.
看似不可能，但它就在眼前
It seems impossible, but there it is.
- 固定环绕轨道，史波克 - 是，舰长
- Hold us in a fixed orbit, Mr. Spock. - Affirmative, captain.
- 还是没有对方的回复？ - 没有，舰长
- Still no response, communications? - None, captain.
传送我们下去，让安全人员待命
We'll beam down. Alert security.
准备传送外遣队到地面
Prepare to transport landing party to surface.
我们将在求救信号源附近登陆
We'll land in the vicinity of the distress signal now being received.
一模一样
Identical.
20世纪早期的地球就是这样
Earth, as it was in the early 1900s.
更像是中期，舰长，大约1960年
More the mid-1900s, I would say, captain, approximately 1960.
但人都跑哪儿去啦？
But where is everybody?
仪器显示，这里发生过自然劣化
Readings indicate that natural deterioration has been taking place
至少持续了好几个世纪
on this planet for at least several centuries.
- 那就是说人都死啦？ - 还不好说，文书
- You mean there's no one alive? - Not conclusive, yeoman.
看来求救信号是自动发出的
The evidence would suggest that the distress signal is automated.
不可思议
You know, this is marvellous.
这是我见过最老最破的建筑群
The most horrible conglomeration of antique architecture I’ve ever seen.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
我的！
Mine!
是我的！
It's mine!
这是我的！这是我的！
It's mine! It’s mine!
我的！我的！是我的！
Mine! Mine! It’s mine!
它坏了
It's broke.
有人把它弄坏了
Somebody broke it.
修理
Fix.
能修好它吗？
Somebody, please fix.
它肯定还能修好
Of course somebody will fix it.
虽然相貌扭曲，可的确近似人类
Definitely humanoid, in spite of the distortion.
可心智却和小孩一样
But with the mind of a child.
- 老骨头，怎么回事？ - 某种癫痫
- Bones, what is it? - A seizure of some type.
- 我们会帮你的 - 撒谎！
- We wanna help you. - Liar!
骗子，骗子
Fibber, fibber.
骗子，骗子！
Fibber, fibber!
骗子！骗子！
Fibber! Fibber! Fibber! Fibber!
Fibber! Fibber!
它死了
It's dead.
- 不敢相信 - 什么？
- It's incredible. - What is?
它新陈代谢的速度
Its metabolic rate.
快得无法想象，就像自燃
It's impossibly high, as if it's burning itself up.
就刚才那几分钟，他老了一个世纪
Almost as if it aged a century in just the past few minutes.
跟我来！
Come on!
- 这是什么时候的东西？ - 大概300年前的
- How old is this thing? - About 300 years.
出来
Come out.
我们并无恶意
We mean you no harm.
别伤害我，求你了
Don't hurt me, please.
我不会的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
别过来，求你了，我什么都没做
No, please, don't. I didn't do anything.
- 我不会伤害你的 - 别过来，求你了
- I won't hurt you. - No, please, don't.
- 我只想和你谈谈 - 不，不要，不要伤…
- I only wanna talk to you. - No, don't, don't hurt--
- 出来吧 - 不，不要，求求你
- Come on. - No. Don't, please.
- 我不会伤害你，来吧 - 别伤害我
- I won't hurt you. Come on. - Don't hurt me.
- 不要… - 没关系
- Don't-- - It's all right.
- 不… - 来这边
- No-- - Come here.
我们不会伤害你，亲爱的，我们是朋友，别怕
We won't hurt you, sweetheart. We're your friends. No.
带警卫到外面搜查一下
Take the guards, have a look outside.
看是否有放射性物质，化学污染，或是其他生命迹象
Radioactive readings, chemical pollutions, any further sign of life.
是，舰长
Right, captain.
她经历了什么事？怎么这么怕我们？
I wonder what happened to her that she should be so terrified of us.
可我还记得你们这些“大大”做的事
But I remember the things you "grups" did.
烧东西，大喊大叫，伤害别人
Burning and yelling, hurting people.
这种事我们从未做过
We didn't do anything like that.
现在也不会吗？
You're not going to hurt?
不会，当然不会
No, of course not.
我们是来帮忙的
We're here to help.
“大大”从不会帮忙
Grups don't help.
但我们会
But we will.
这儿发生了什么？
What happened here?
人都哪去了？
Where is everybody?
你知道
You know.
我不知道
No, I don't.
你能告诉我吗？
Won't you tell me?
你想玩“胡闹”吗？你想跟我玩，可我不会
You got a "foolie," is that it? And you want me to play, but I can't.
我不知道规则，我得知道规则
I don't know the rules. I've got to know the rules.
- “胡闹”？ - 一种游戏，你知道的
- Foolie? - A game, you know.
玩游戏就得知道游戏规则
You can't play a game without rules.
即使“大大”也得知道
Even grups ought to know that.
- 谁是“大大”？ - 你们
- What are grups? - You are.
“恩里斯”长大了就是“大大”【恩里斯指这里的小孩】
They were when "onlies" get old.
成年人
Grown-ups.
你刚才说这些“大大”做坏事
You said something about the grups doing bad things.
大喊大叫，打人，烧东西
Yelling, hurting, burning.
他们生病的时候就变这样了
That was when they started to get sick in the before time.
我们躲了起来然后他们就不见了
We hid, then they were gone.
我这样做对吗？
Am I doing all right?
你做的很好
You're doing fine.
你说“大大”们都生病了
You said the grups got sick.
是不是因为这样他们才不见了？
Is that why there aren't any of them around?
是，他们都死了
Yes. They died.
但是在做了这些可怕的事情后
But that was after the awful things.
是瘟疫，舰长，只有瘟疫才会这样
A plague, captain. That could explain a lot of it.
孩子们呢？就是这的“恩里斯”
But what about the children, the onlies?
可怕的事情有没有影响到他们？
Didn't the awful things affect them?
当然没有，我们不是还活着吗？
Of course not. We're here, aren't we?
- 除你以外还有多少？ - 都活着
- More of you? How many? - All there are.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
米莉
Miri.
名字真好听…
Pretty name...
人也很漂亮
...for a pretty young woman.
漂亮？
Pretty?
非常漂亮
Very pretty.
警卫！
Guards!
掩护我
Cover me.
孩子，舰长，有很多孩子
Children, captain. Lots of them.
无法接近他们，一走近，他们便一哄而散
We couldn't begin to get close to them. They just seemed to scurry away.
- 像动物似的，只有孩子 - 米莉说所有大人都死了
- Like animals, only children. - Miri said all the adults died.
攻击我们的那个家伙绝对不是小孩
That creature which attacked us was certainly no child.
导致它死亡的原因也许就是女孩说的那种病
Perhaps it died of the disease the girl's talking about.
这里肯定有记录可寻
There must be records somewhere.
可以解开我们的疑问
And answers to some of our questions.
米莉？
Miri?
你知道医生以前都在哪工作吗？
Do you know any buildings where the doctors used to work?
知道，我还知道他们的药品在哪
Yes, I know that. Them and their pills and things.
- 能带我去吗？ - 那里好恐怖
- Will you take me there? - That's a bad place.
这很重要
It's important.
- 算我求你 - 好吧
- Please. - All right.
你也有名字吗？
Do you have a name too?
- 有，我叫吉姆 - 这名字我喜欢
- Yes. It's Jim. - I like that name.
那就好
Good.
我也喜欢你的名字
I like yours too.
人也很喜欢
I like you.
真的？
Do you really?
我不会骗你
I wouldn't lie to you.
我也不会骗你，吉姆
I wouldn't lie to you either, Jim.
我记得这的大大，你不一样，你是好人
I remember the grups, but you're nice. You're different.
多谢夸奖
Why, thank you.
开始了，我就知道会这样
It's already starting. I knew it would.
就像这里的大大一样
Just like it did with the grups.
它会蔓延到你全身，你会大叫，会伤害所有人
It'll spread all over you. You'll yell, you'll try to hurt everybody,
最后你会死，我就知道会这样，我就知道
and then you'll die. I knew it would, I knew it would.
舰长日志，星历2713.6
Captain's log, stardate 2713.6:
米莉带我们去的那栋楼
The building Miri led us to also housed
还有一座自动传输站
an automatic transmission station,
就是那的信号，把我们引到这里
which sent out the signals that drew us to this planet.
我们还发现
we also discovered something else:
所有人都得了一种莫名的疾病
That the blue splotches characteristic of the unknown disease
身上都出现了蓝斑，除了史波克
had appeared on each of us, with the exception of Mr. spock.
这栋楼有间化验室，设备齐全
There was a well-equipped laboratory in the building.
麦考伊医生采集了每个人身上的组织细胞
Dr. McCoy took tissue samples of each of us
试图分离出病毒组织
in an attempt to isolate the organism responsible.
真是名副其实的细菌动物园
A veritable zoo of bacteria.
传送一台生物电脑和一台便携式电子显微镜
Beam down a bio-computer and a portable electronic microscope.
我在和病毒打交道
lf I'm gonna be dealing with viruses,
需要更好的仪器
I'm gonna need better equipment than I have here.
- 好的，医生，寇克舰长？ - 什么事，上尉？
- Yes, doctor. Captain Kirk? - Yes, lieutenant?
我们有人想自愿下来帮忙，长官
I've got volunteers standing by ready to help you, sir.
不管发生什么，任何人都不许离开星舰
Under no circumstances do I want anyone to beam down from the ship.
必须防止病菌进一步蔓延
We can't take any chances with further contamination.
- 可舰长，要是你病情加重… - 我的命令依然有效，上尉
- But, captain, if you become too ill-- - My orders still stand, lieutenant.
你们可以帮我整理电脑资料库并待命，通话完毕
You can help by clearing the computer banks and standing by. Kirk out.
老骨头
Bones.
为什么史波克身上没有这种病症？
Why do you think the symptoms haven't appeared on Mr. Spock?
不知道
I don't know.
也许这些小病菌或微生物什么的
Probably the little bugs, or whatever they are,
觉得绿色的血液味道不好吧
have no appetite for green blood.
看来红色的血液显然会成为人类的缺点
Being a red-blooded human obviously has its disadvantages.
瞧桌上这玩意儿可以当文物了，大夫
Now, there you have a museum piece, doctor.
透镜型，手动操作，光感的…
Lens-type, manually operated, light-activated--
就不能消停一下吗，史波克？
Spare me the analysis, Mr. Spock, please?
能用就不错了
It's enough that it works.
扩散的好快，我就知道
It spreads real fast, I know.
只要变成大大，它就会遍布全身
When you're old, it covers you like anything.
“就生命延长实验项目的…
"Intermediate experimentation report project on life...
中期报告”
...prolongation."
“进度报告，遗传部门，生命延长项目”
"Progress report, genetics section. Life prolongation project."
原来如此
So that's what it was.
生命延长
Life prolongation.
进展得不太走运吧？
Didn't have much luck, did they?
舰长日志
Captain's log:
麦考伊医生的生物电脑及便携式电子显微镜
Dr. McCoy's bio-computer and a portable electronic microscope
已从进取号传送下来
have been beamed down from the Enterprise.
它们将会和船上的电脑资料库相连
They will be used in conjunction with computer banks onboard ship.
管状物，极具多样性
Tubular, with extreme multiplicability.
类似核酸，把查到的信息告诉我
Appear to have affinity for nucleic acids. Give me what you have.
- 三百年前的事，舰长 - 所有的成年人都死了
- This was 300 years ago, captain. - All the adults are dead.
只有孩子们活下来了
Only the children are left alive.
但孩子们会长大成人
But children become adults.
至少目前为止他们还活着
At least they have up to now.
医生…
Doctor...
在进入青春期时
...there are certain glandular changes which take place
有些腺体会发生变化，对吗？
upon entering puberty, are there not?
当然，改变了整个身体系统
Of course. It changes the entire body system.
你知道的
You know that.
当然知道，怎么了？
Of course you know that. Why?
这里的孩子们会不会是
Is it not possible that these children here,
由于进入青春期，而感染的疾病呢？
as they enter puberty, contract the disease?
那就能解释为什么没有成年人了
That would explain why there are no adults.
腺体，青春期后期，可能是这样
Glandular, post-pubescent. It could be.
还是不合逻辑，不能理解的
It's illogical. It does not follow.
这颗行星上所有的成年人都在300年前死了…
All the adults on this planet died 300 years ago...
…但现在大街上还有孩子
...but there are children in the streets.
他们进入青春期就会死去
Who die when they enter adolescence.
但是他们的生命怎么延续的呢？
But how do they keep their line going?
还有一件事，舰长
One thing, captain.
如果她自从小女孩起就像野兽一样没人管
If she were a wild animal ever since she's been a little girl,
你如何解释她愿意和我们呆在一起？
how do you explain that she wants to stay with us?
孤独？我不知道，好奇？
Loneliness? I don't know. Curiosity?
我想孩子们天生就需要成年人陪伴
I think children have an instinctive need for adults.
他们想被告知对错与否
They want to be told right and wrong.
这种情况中可能还有其他感情因素，舰长
There may be other emotions at work in this case, captain.
她喜欢你，吉姆
She likes you, Jim.
她正在成长为一个女人
She's becoming a woman.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
- 我是史波克 - 下面是您要的数据
- Spock here. - Here are those figures you asked for.
12的10次方
Twelve to the tenth power.
代谢率，72%
Metabolic rate, 72 percent.
核酸量降至正常水平的33%
Production of nucleic acids reduced to 33 percent of normal.
惯用时序级数，3.6分之100
Conventional chronological progression, 100 by 3.6.
收到，上尉
Acknowledged, lieutenant.
我现在知道他们的算法了
I have their calculations now.
再试试，看看能不能在其他方面发现点什么
Try again. See if you can find anything outside.
嘿
Hey.
帮我擦擦那张桌子，好吗？
Clean up that desk for me, will you?
- 好啊，吉姆 - 谢谢
- All right, Jim. - Thank you.
按照他们的生命延续计划
According to their life prolongation plan,
他们认为正在实现的算法是
what they thought they were accomplishing,
在实际时间的每100年内，一个人只长大一个月
a person would age only one month for every 100 years of real time.
100年，仅长大一个月？
One hundred years, and only one month?
没错，文书
Exactly, yeoman.
显而易见，由于某处有误算
Evidently, through some miscalculation,
导致这种病毒在很短的时间段内
this virus annihilated the entire adult population
摧毁了整个成年人群，只留下了孩子
in a very short period, leaving only the children.
但那就意味着这些孩子…
But that means these children...
应该已经非常老了
Could very well be immensely old.
那就回答了这个问题
That would certainly answer the question
他们的父母当年发生了什么事情
of what happened to their parents.
- 很好的答案 - 孩子们永远长不大
- Answers it very well. - Children who never age.
永远的儿童时代，可以尽情玩耍，没有责任
Eternal childhood filled with play, no responsibilities.
简直像一场梦
It's almost like a dream.
我不会太靠近这个梦的，文书
I wouldn't examine that dream too closely, yeoman.
可能结果并不是很美好
It might not turn out to be very pretty.
几天前，或者一个星期前，那个袭击我们的生物
A few days ago, or a week ago, that creature that attacked us
可能一直和米莉一样
could have been just like Miri.
在这颗行星上的孩子进入青春期
A child entering puberty on this planet
就意味着死刑
means a death sentence.
你认为她知道吗？
Do you suppose she knows?
我认为她不知道
I don't think so.
哦，如果他们像史波克说的那么老
Well, if they're as old as Spock claims,
他们一定了解一些当年的情况
they must have some idea of what's happening.
对这里没有成年人能做些解释
There's no adult interpretation.
我认为我们得和这些孩子打交道，他们可能很老了
I think we're dealing with children. Immensely old, perhaps,
但毕竟他们还是孩子
but nonetheless children.
我得从其他人身上下手
I've gotta do something about the others.
那很难，如果我们都见不到他们的话
Difficult, if we can't even get a glimpse of them.
你不能接近其他的孩子吗？
You couldn't get close to the other kids?
不可能，他们很了解这个地区
Impossible. They know the area too well.
就像老鼠
Like mice.
我要试一试
I'm gonna try.
米莉
Miri.
过来一下
Come here.
- 你想和我一起转转吗？ - 当然
- You wanna go someplace with me? - Sure.
那个小女孩…
That little girl--
比你至少年长300岁，文书
Is at least 300 years older than you are, yeoman.
想一想吧
Think about it.
米莉跟他们在一起，为什么？为什么？
Miri is with them. Why? Why?
- 你打算怎么办，雅恩？ - 我不…我不知道
- What you gonna do, Jahn? - I don't-- I don't know.
我知道我们怎么办了
I know what we've gotta do.
他们比我们看到的人要多，在某个地方
There's more of them than we see. Somewhere.
可能在天上，某个地方
Up in the sky, maybe. Somewhere.
他们一直互相交谈
They talk to each other all the time.
你们知道大大吧，你们知道大大都干什么
You know grups. You know what they do.
伤害、杀戮…
The hurting, the killing...
- 我记得，雅恩，那是以前… - 没错
- I remember, Jahn, the way it was-- - That's right.
就和以前一样
The way it was in the before time.
他们用小盒子与其他的大大说话
They talk to the other grups with these little boxes.
既然如此，如果他们没有了那些小盒子…
Now, if they didn't have those little boxes...
…他们就孤立了
...they'd be all alone.
但是他们看不见我们，我们藏起来了
But they don't see us. We hide.
- 找啊，找啊，找不到我 - 找啊，找啊，找不到我
- Ollie, ollie, oxen free - Ollie, ollie, oxen free
- 找啊，找啊，找不到我 - 不！
- Ollie, ollie, oxen free - No!
这不是游戏
It's not a game.
这是实战
It's real.
他们很危险，他们是大大，你们不明白吗？
They're dangerous. They're grups. Don't you understand?
雅恩
Jahn.
好吧，咱们藏起来
All right, let's hide.
死了
Dead.
我不太明白，我的相位枪没有设定成致死状态啊
I don't understand it. My phaser wasn't set to kill.
她叫路易丝
Her name was Louise.
事情发生时她只是比我年长一些
She was a little bit older than I am when it happened.
噢，吉姆
Oh, Jim.
数据已经输入计算机，史波克先生，候命中
Data has been fed into the computers, Mr. Spock. stand by.
收到
Acknowledged.
这些够了吗，吉姆？
Are these enough, Jim?
如果你不介意的话，我们可能用的再多些
We could use some more, if you don't mind.
不，我不介意
No, I don't mind.
你在这找到的不应该有问题啊？
There couldn't be any doubt about what you've found here?
在发病后，这家伙在死前的几个星期作了记录
This fellow made these notes in the last weeks, after the disaster began.
我先不管这些后面的记录，他说他自己病得严重
I disregard these last entries. He said himself he was too sick,
没法确定他还没有疯，我同意
too far gone to be sure he wasn't already mad, and I agree.
但是按照前面的记录
But based on the entries he made before that,
我知道我们还剩多少时间
I know how much time we have.
船上的电脑会验证我的数据
The ship's computers will verify my figures.
只是时间问题，我们全都会变疯
Only a matter of time before we all go mad,
互相残杀，直到最后的那个人自己毁掉自己
destroy each other, till the last of us finally destroys himself.
米莉呢？
What about Miri?
我们的猜测是对的，他们进入青春期就会染上疾病
Our guess was correct. They contract the disease as they enter puberty
他们的新陈代谢有了变化，笔记还提示了
and their metabolism changes. The notes would indicate
不太精确的时间，也就1个月左右
that it doesn't become acute for a month or so.
我估计她可能还剩5、6个星期
I estimate she has perhaps five or six weeks left.
我们呢？
What about us?
受害者越年长，疾病的发展速度越快
The older the victim, the more rapid the progress of the disease.
那你呢？
And you?
好像疾病对你不感兴趣
The disease doesn't seem to be interested in you.
我是携带者，无论怎样，我也不能回星舰了
I am a carrier. Whatever happens, I can't go back to the ship.
可我确实想回星舰，舰长
And I do want to go back to the ship, captain.
当然，史波克先生
Of course, Mr. Spock.
我们还是不知道我们要对抗的是什么吗？
We still don't know what we're fighting.
是啊，但我们知道了诱因，致命有多迅速
No, but we know what it is, and how fast it does it.
它的进程，我们很快就会从五脏六腑感受到
It's progressing. We'll begin to feel it inside soon.
高烧，手脚剧烈疼痛
Intense fever, great pain in the extremities,
视觉模糊
fuzziness of vision.
当然，那些只是早期症状，后面症状会越来越多
Of course, those are the early symptoms. There'll be more.
你确定我们剩下的时间吗？
Are you certain about the time we have left?
我认为我的计算准确无误
I presume my calculations are correct.
- 有没有可能…？ - 外遣队，这里是进取号
- Is there any possibility--? - Landing party, this is the Enterprise.
我是史波克
Spock here.
计算机显示还有170小时，史波克先生
Computer indicates 170 hours, Mr. Spock.
确认了，舰长，我们还有7天时间
Verified, captain. We have seven days.
舰长日志，补充
Captain's log, supplement:
今天是我们剩余7天中的第2天，还没有什么发现
It is the second day of the seven left to us. We've found nothing.
进取号全体实验室、计算机都待命中，准备实施援助
Enterprise is standing by with its labs, computers, ready to assist us,
但是没有数据，无从下手
but there is no data, no starting point.
我想我找到了
I think I've found it.
- 贾尼丝，带米莉走走 - 是，长官
- Janice, take Miri for a walk. - Yes, sir.
只有一半的完整性
Only one half intact.
但你知道他们当时要做什么了？
But do you know what they were up to?
差不多吧
More or less.
他们的办法是造出新系列的疾病
The idea was to create a new series of diseases,
其病毒的反应链意味着生命的延续
a chain reaction of viruses meant essentially to extend the life
让人类细胞无限制成长
of the human cell immeasurably.
不幸的是，他们没有成功，我们已经看到了结果
Unfortunately, they weren't successful. We've seen the results.
你们两人必须再现他们的想法，如果能分离出病毒
You two will have to recreate their thinking. lf you can isolate that virus,
你们就能制造疫苗了
you'll be able to develop a vaccine.
就这样，舰长？我们还有5天，你知道的
Is that all, captain? We have five days, you know.
我知道
I know.
孩子们
Children.
- 发现什么了？你呢？ - 没有，什么也没发现
- Anything? You? - No. Nothing.
是通讯器，舰长
The communicators, captain.
通讯器不见了
They're gone.
吉姆，我们绝对要用到通讯器
Jim, we've absolutely gotta have those communicators.
没有通讯器，我们就没有了计算机
Without them, we don't have the computers.
没有计算机，我们就没有一丝机会
And without the computers, we don't have a chance.
舰长日志，星历2717.3
Captain's log, stardate 2717.3:
我们还剩3天零7个小时
Three days, seven hours left to us.
研究表明该地区的食物供给余量
lnvestigation proves that the supply of food left in the area
极度不足，除非做点什么
is running dangerously low. Unless something is done,
否则孩子们将在几个月后挨饿
the children will staeve in a few months.
另外，疾病也影响了我们每一个人
In addition, the disease is working on each of us
按照麦考伊医生的预言，我们的脾气越来越差
according to Dr. McCoy's prediction. Our tempers are growing short,
我们不像2天前那么融洽
and we are no further along than we were two days ago.
- 你还没什么发现吗？ - 你想尝试一下吗？
- Haven't you found a thing yet? - Would you like to take a crack at it?
不！不！不！
No! No! No!
不！
No!
我很烦，舰长，非常烦
I'm upset, captain. So upset.
在星舰上的时候，我一直努力想让你看我的腿
Back on the ship, I used to try to get you to look at my legs.
舰长…
Captain...
…看看我的腿吧
...look at my legs.
我们都很害怕
We're all frightened.
吉姆，我有发现了
Jim, I found something.
实验的最后一个载片，我没有调节好
The last slide I examined, I failed to make the necessary adjustment
- 没有让它慢下来… - 无所谓，你发现什么了？
- for the slowing down-- - Never mind. What did you find?
疾病，舰长，300年前他们创造的疾病
The disease, captain. The one they created 300 years ago.
- 有机会了！ - 有机会
- There's a chance! - A chance.
至少现在赛跑开始了
At least it's a race now.
而我们刚浪费了一分钟
And we've just wasted a minute.
我承认那会有些乐子，米莉，但能行吗？
I'll admit it would be some foolie, Miri, but do you think it'd work?
我知道，我知道
I know, I know.
你认为我没听到他们谈话吗？
Don't you think I've heard them talk?
他们没有多少时间去做他们那蠢事了
They have such little time to do this dumb thing of theirs,
那些狗拿耗子的事了
this "buttinsky" thing.
如果我们把她引走，那个文书
And if we get her away, that yeoman,
那就可以少对付一个人
that's one person less to start off with.
但怎么做呢，米莉？如果他们很忙的话
But how, Miri? If they're so busy,
如果他们有紧急大事的话
if they're gonna have the big emergency,
- 你怎么把她弄走呢？ - 很简单
- how are you gonna get her away? - It's easy.
她老是问我最小的恩里斯的事情
She's always asking me about the youngest little onlies, the little ones.
“如果他们生病了怎么办？谁照顾他们？”
"What if they get sick? Who takes care of them?
“他们吃的够吗？他们在哪里睡觉呢？”
Do they have enough to eat? Where do they sleep?"
我只要告诉她你们当中的一个受伤倒下了
I'll just tell her one of you fell down and got hurt.
- 说我，说是我 - 好的，就说是你
- Me, say it's me. - All right, you.
但大大什么事情都知道
But grups, they know things and all that.
就算他们少了一个人也能照旧想办法
You know, I bet they'll be able to do it with one person less.
不是一个人
Not one.
两个
Two.
因为他会去找她
Because he'll try to find her.
谁啊，谁会去找她，米莉
Who? Who will, Miri?
舰长
The captain.
他会去找她，但他一定找不到
He'll try to find her, but he won't.
- 多情的先生 - 多情
- Mr. Lovey-dovey. - Lovey-dovey.
敲，敲，敲死他，敲死他
Bonk, bonk on the head. Bonk, bonk! Bonk, bonk!
敲死他，敲死他，敲死他
Bonk, bonk! Bonk, bonk! Bonk, bonk!
Bonk, bonk! Bonk, bonk! Bonk, bonk! Bonk, bonk!
- 看上去是了 - 氮化合物循环，应该是的
- It looks right. - The nitrogen cycle? It has to be.
是，可问题是
Yeah, but the question is:
要用多少的量呢
What's the dosage?
这真是个好问题
That is a very good question.
米莉，她去哪里了？贾尼丝去哪里了？
Where is she, Miri? Where is she, Miri? Where is Janice?
你干什么啊？我怎么知道？
What's the matter with you? How should I know?
她去哪儿了？
Where is she?
- 她出什么事了？ - 你还好吗？
- Has something happened to her? - Don't you feel all right?
不，我不好，我们都不好
No, I don't feel all right! None of us feel all right!
你难道没看到现在的状况吗？
Can't you see what's going on?
吉姆，我不希望你有事啊
Jim, I don't want anything to happen to you.
- 我要去找贾尼丝 - 这还不够，舰长
- I've gotta find Janice. - That's not all, captain.
我们还要找到通讯器
We've got to find those communicators.
我们尽力了，史波克，我们已经够尽力了
We're trying, Mr. Spock. We're trying hard.
这还不够
That's not good enough!
这可能就是解药了，但我们没有星舰上的电脑就不能测试
This could be it, but we can't test it without the ship's computers.
我们必须找到通讯器，吉姆
We've got to have those communicators, Jim.
这就是那疫苗吗
This is the vaccine?
是不是只有电脑检测了才知道
That's what the computers will tell us.
没有电脑，这有可能就是一杯致死的毒药
Without them, it could be a beaker full of death.
你听到了吗？
Did you hear them?
- 我们只有几个小时的命了 - 这不关我的事
- We only have a few hours left. - I don't care.
这当然关你的事
You've got to care.
米莉
Miri.
我要告诉你一些事
I'm gonna tell you something.
你
You...
你的朋友，所有的恩里斯，都会得上这种病的
...your friends, all the onlies, are gonna get the disease
除非我们研究的疫苗成功了
unless we succeed in what we're doing.
你也看到了你的一些朋友得上这种病了
You've seen some of your friends get it.
- 那只是偶尔 - 这不是偶尔，是必然，米莉
- Sometimes it happens-- - Not sometimes, all the times, Miri!
只要你一开始长大，你现在就是
As soon as you start growing up, the way you are.
你知道你为什么不喜欢玩游戏了吗？
Don't you know why you don't like to play games anymore?
为什么看你朋友的方式和以前不同了？
Why you don't see your friends the way you used to?
那是因为你已经在长大了
It's because you're becoming a young woman.
而你
And...
在长大的同时，你也在感染上这种病毒，你们都会
...the moment you become a young woman, you get the disease, all of you.
不是的，那只是偶然情况
That's not true. It just happens sometimes.
全都是这样的，米莉
All the time, Miri!
你现在已经感染上了
It's happening to you right now!
你看看，米莉，病毒已经渗透到你身体里了
Look at it. Look at it, Miri! It's in you!
- 不！ - 你看看！
- No! - Look at it!
不！
No! No!
不对，你玩的不对，我和你说了，当老师
No, you got the wrong game. A teacher, I told you.
老师会说什么呢，嗯？
Now what does a teacher say, huh?
对啊
Yeah.
学习，学习！否则敲死你，坏孩子
Study, study, study! Or bonk, bonk, bad kid.
- 这一点都不好玩 - 这是“胡闹”游戏
- It's not funny. - It's a foolie.
你们想拿我怎么样？
What are you gonna do with me?
你以为我会告诉你吗？
You think I'd tell you?
米莉
Miri.
- 你不应该来这里 - 我知道
- You're not supposed to be here. - I know.
怎么了，出什么事了
What's the matter? Something go wrong?
- 没事 - 那好
- No. - Okay, then.
那就别站在门口了，进来吧
Just don't stand there in the doorway. Come on in.
- 听他说 - 你给我听着，米莉
- Listen to him. - You listen, Miri!
我听了，否则你认为我为什么带他来
I did. Why do you think I brought him here?
- 告诉他们吧，吉姆 - 告诉他们吧，吉姆
- Tell them, Jim. - "Tell them, Jim."
告诉他们吧，吉姆
- Tell them, Jim. - Tell them, Jim!
Tell them, Jim! Tell them, Jim! Tell them, Jim! Tell them, Jim!
- 告诉他们吧，吉姆！ - 大家听我说
- Tell them, Jim! Tell them, Jim! - Listen to me.
- 听我说！ - 他在课堂上喧哗
- Listen to me! - Yelling in the classroom.
大家看，他是坏学生
Look at him. A very bad citizen.
这不是游戏，这一开始就不是游戏
This isn't a game. There never was a game.
- 叫警察叔叔抓他！ - 我就是警察
- Call the police! - I'm the police!
- 你只要不乖我就敲死你 - 你演的是老师
- Bonk, bonk, unless you're good. - You're the teacher!
我两个都是，敲死你，敲死你
I got two jobs! Bonk, bonk!
听我说，你们偷走了我们的通讯器
Listen to me! You've got our communicators...
我们对着说话的那个盒子
...the boxes we talk into.
我们需要用它们来和星舰对话
We need them to talk to the ship.
别再吵啦
No blah, blah, blah!
如果我们不能和星舰联络上
Because if we don't talk to the ship...
如果你们不帮助我们
...if you don't help us...
以后就再也没有游戏可以玩了
...there won't be any games anymore.
以后什么都没有了
There won't be anything.
什么都没有
Nothing.
不会有大大，也不会有恩里斯
No grups, no onlies.
最后谁都不会活下来
Nobody left...
永远都不会有了
...forever and ever.
舰长小心
Captain!
现在听我说
Now listen to me.
你们一定要帮我们，现在还来得及
You've got to help us before it's too late.
放了贾尼丝，趁现在还来得及快把通讯器还给我们
Let Janice go. Give me those communicators before it's too late!
你们也见到你们的朋友一个个长大后都变了
You've seen your friends change one by one as they grew up.
你们有见到例外的吗？
Did you ever see one of them not change?
一个接一个，他们都得上了这种病，都变成了
One by one, they got the disease, and they became like--
你们害怕的东西，就像路易丝
Like-- Like those creatures you're afraid of, like Louise.
一个接一个，他们都会变，染上这病毒
One by one, they changed and got the disease.
就像我得的这种病，像米莉得的这种
The disease, like I’ve got, like Miri has.
你们知道我在说什么
You understand what I'm talking about.
你们已经不是小孩子了，我们能帮助你们
You're not babies. We can help you.
坏大大，敲死他，敲死他
Naughty grup! Bonk, bonk!
- 敲死他！ - 不，求你们了，不要
- Bonk, bonk! - No! Please! No!
你也会得上的，也就是几个月的事
It's waiting for you. Maybe only a matter of months.
听他说，他说的是事实
Listen to him. He's telling the truth.
- 他真滑稽，他觉得他很滑稽 - 敲死他，敲死他，打死他
- He's funny. He thinks he's funny. - Bonk, bonk! Hit him!
看看我的手臂
Look at my arms!
这也会发生在你们身上
That's what's gonna happen to you...
- 除非让我帮你们 - 敲死他，敲死他，打他
- ...unless you let me help you. - Bonk, bonk! Hit him!
- 敲死他，敲死他！ - 那些最小的孩子
- Bonk, bonk! - And the little ones...
你们死后他们怎么办…
What's gonna happen to them after you've gone...
你们变成路易丝那样，他们还在这
...after you've turned into creatures like Louise? Oh, they'll still be here.
但他们也不会活太久，因为食物不够了，你们吃完了
But not for long, because the food's all gone. You've eaten it.
估计只能吃上六个月了，就只有这些了，没东西可吃了
Maybe six months left. That's all. And then nothing left to eat.
没人能照顾他们了，他们也会死的
Nobody left to take care of them. They'll die too.
看看我的手臂，我已经得上这病了，他是说实话
Look at my arm, Jahn. It’s happening to me. He's telling the truth.
- 他们是大大！ - 敲死他，敲死他
- They're grups! - Bonk, bonk!
敲死他，敲死他，敲死他，敲死他！
Bonk, bonk! Bonk, bonk! Bonk, bonk! Bonk, bonk!
- 敲死他，敲死他！ - 好吧，你们想玩是吧
- Bonk, bonk! - All right, you want a foolie?
我谅你不敢
All right. I dare you.
你绝对不敢
I double dare you.
看看我脸上的血，再看看你们的手
Look at the blood on my face. Now look at your hands.
你们手上的血
Blood on your hands.
告诉我是谁在伤害别人
Now who's doing the hurting?
不是大大，是你们在伤害，吼叫，或许杀戮
Not the grups. It's you hurting, yelling, maybe killing.
就像你们记忆中害怕的大大一样
Just like the grups you remember, and the creatures you're afraid of.
你们的行为和他们一样，你们最后也会变得和他们一样
You're acting like them, and you're gonna be just like them
除非你们让我帮你们
unless you let me help you.
我是大大没错
I'm a grup...
但我想帮你们
...and I want to help you.
我恳求你们了，让我帮你们吧
I'm begging you, let me help you.
否则就什么都没有了
Or there won't be anything left at all.
拜托你们了
Please.
我们没时间等通讯器拿回来了
We can't wait for those communicators any longer.
- 我们一定要等着，这疫苗很可能是致命的 - 病毒是致命的没错
- We must. The vaccine could be fatal. - The disease certainly is.
我们还能活多久，几小时，几分钟？
How long do we have left? Hours? Minutes?
你到底还想等什么？
How much longer do you wanna wait?
吵架一点意义都没有，我去看看舰长那边
Bickering is pointless. I’ll check on the captain's progress.
史波克
Spock!
- 他死了吗，史波克先生？ - 还没有
- Is he dead, Mr. Spock? - Not yet.
还有三小时十一分钟，谢谢你，上尉
Three hours, 11 minutes left. Thank you, lieutenant.
把频道打开，准备好电脑
Keep this channel open. Clear your computers.
- 麦考伊怎么了？ - 他自己注射了疫苗
- What happened to McCoy? - He injected himself with the vaccine.
我发现他的时候已经昏迷不醒了
He was unconscious when I found him.
你看他的脸
Look at his face.
蓝斑在消褪
The blemishes are fading.
是的
They're fading.
医生的想法真心不懂
I never will understand the medical mind.
这是不是件好事，米莉？
Is this supposed to be a good thing, Miri?
当然是啦
Of course it is.
他们还只是一群孩子
They were just children.
- 把他们留给医疗队… - “还是孩子”
- To leave them with a medical team-- - Just children.
他们都要三百多岁了
Three hundred years old and more.
我已经联络了太空总部，他们已经派去了老师和顾问
I've already contacted Space Central. They'll send teachers, advisers.
- 我猜还要带上训导员吧 - 他们会没事的
- And truant officers, I presume. - They'll be all right.
米莉，她真的很爱你，你知道吗？
Miri... She really loved you, you know.
是啊
Yes.
我从来不和比我年纪大的女人恋爱，文书小姐
I never get involved with older women, yeoman.
- 史波克先生？ - 什么吩咐，舰长
- Mr. Spock? - Captain?
- 全速前进，一级曲速 - 是，舰长，一级曲速
- Full ahead, warp factor 1. - Warp factor 1, captain.
本集结束
谢谢观赏